the clo all Napa Valley cabinet 2021
will be the yes second one yes all right
man sir
[Music]
Heights sellers St Wine sellers silvert
welcome to T thank you well well I was
actually just um telling the fans and
our friends that about how there's a lot
of changes over the past 20 30 years in
Napa Valley a lot of the premium
wineries got sold and uh how how it's
very precious that you actually came
back and then start being the family of
your the founding which is your
grandfather and being very Hands-On and
also clal is one of the few first brands
that we start promoting introducing
Taiwan so can you kind of give our fans
a a quick summary about the history and
how it all got started closed up
absolutely so clal started back in 1972
was our first vintage but the story of
clal really started in 1969 when my
grandfather John glet his mother's
family were originally from Bordeaux
they were in the wine merchant business
in Bordeaux dating back to the uh the
late 1700s and he was spending time
there trying to figure out where and how
he was going to start his own wine
project and in 1969 he was introduced to
a young wine maker uh who grew up in
Bordeaux named Bernard Porte and the two
of them uh became fast friends and then
decided to go on an adventure to seek
and find a place outside of Bordeaux
outside of Europe where you could make
world class uh Bordeaux brial wine and
that Journey began obviously in Bordeaux
uh they traveled to Australia South
America both Chile and Argentina we
spend quite a bit of time in South
Africa and then in California where they
ultimately picked a spot which we now
know today as dags Leep District in NAA
Valley oh wow so so
uh your grandfather uh and your father
they never really managed the winery
Hands-On dayto day no so when when clal
started Bernard be became the the wine
maker and the general manager yes my
grandfather had a number of
entrepreneurial um projects that he
started in his lifetime I think one
thing that was always consistent was he
had the vision but he was always looking
for the right partner to help operate
mhm cuz that wasn't his background and
so Bernard really carried that torch for
the better part of 35 years so with my
generation taking over the ownership it
gave us an opportunity to think a little
differently and how we wanted to manage
the business that's very good actually
it's um it's very precious and and I
think it's especially at this point it's
a very good thing that you decided to
take over and manage it so Olaf why is
it call clal clal uh is French for the
the pocket within the valley or the the
the small Vineyard within the valley
when Bernard uh the founding wine maker
and my grandfather John when they
identified the site that they wanted to
uh to purchase and start this Winery uh
they saw that it it sat in this area
within the valley that really felt like
its own little pocket within the valley
if you've been to the the Stags Lea
District Appalachian within within Napa
Valley you notice that there is the the
Palisades which is really were formed uh
from volcanic rock creates this almost a
hook into the valley and so it creates
this artificial pocket and so when they
saw this place that's as two two two men
from France they they went first to the
mother tongue and that's what came out
oh wow so you're a French origin yes
obviously Bernard grew up both parents
uh were French my grandfather his mother
was French his father was American both
uh French RS uh I think that you're very
familiar with clal really became
renowned and well known because of a
blly tasting that happened 1976 and uh
can you tell us a little bit about it in
your perspective how he got selected how
did Steven spor you know just picked Co
Val instead of hundreds of different
wineries the the perspective I have is
is through stories I was not uh was not
alive in in 1976 but what I can share
through through stories from my
grandfather and Bernard this gentleman
Steven spur he he had been spending time
in California and in particular in Napa
Valley in early 70s and what he was
pleasantly surprised by was here was
this Valley that was quite diverse from
an agricultural standpoint so you had uh
wineries that were popping up in the
valley and there was certainly wine that
had been made in the valley for for the
better part of 100 years but there was
all kinds of other agricultural activity
going on at the time but what he found
when he was spending time there in you
know 70
475 and then up leading up into this
tasting was there were a few few
Wineries and few operations there where
he was really starting to see that there
was great caliber wine and it intrigued
him uh so much so that he wanted to see
how these wines would showcase uh
against some of the the most renowned
wines from the in the world which at
that time you know Bordeaux was really
the um uh the the top of the
yeah and you know I think his his
selection of the wines that he wanted to
to bring into the the competition it I
think it really happened organically you
know he was traveling around getting to
know these these wine makers and these
farmers and you know Bernard uh shared a
his story the first time he met Steven
Spurrier where this gentleman just
showed up in his car drove into the
driveway and and knocked on the door and
Bernard was in the cellar this was at
you know sometime in the February March
time frame so it was Harvest had
finished and they were the wines were in
barrels and they were working on
preparing the next the prior vintage to
go through it's further aging and this
gentleman just knocked on the door and
just wanted to have a chat and see what
they was all about and I think that to
me that's just a fun example of what
this industry was like and its infancy
uh so clal had the opportunity to be one
of the eight red wines selected from
from California it was a great
opportunity for us to participate in
something that really became a defining
moment for for Napa Valley and I think
the really the new world of wine that
that really opened the eyes of to the
world about Napa Valley and really
brought Nappa to the same level as uh as
Bordeaux at that time I mean and
something really interesting in 30 years
later I think the French weren't that
happy when when uh when Nappa got the
first place right for the blind tasting
but it wasn't I mean I think second or
third place places are still French
wineries correct it's just the first
place was Napa and then there were
rumors from my my readings and
recollection that the French wineries
were saying that the napas cannot age
it's you know there's a lot of it's
bubble gum it's this and that but Steven
Spirit did it once again with the same
exact vintage same exact wine but 30
years later and do you know what
happened so in 2006 so they yeah they
they've had a few but so in um in in the
REM match and I think the the French
wine makers they wanted to see
wines uh of exceptional uh quality they
believe will improve with time and so
that was really The Testament the the
greatest Wines in the world they they
age elegantly and we were fortunate
enough to have a a very French approach
and philosophy to wine making and so in
that rematch clel that's amazing not
only CL Val became first place but
second third fourth and fifth are all
now wines so it actually proves that not
only Napa wines are very approachable
and and favorable when they're young but
they can age gracefully and and and
Incredibly and become very comp complex
and and you know different um Aromas
when they age so that that's that's
amazing well I think that's very
interesting if any of the fans haven't
tried CL Val you should really try it's
it's really amazing but if if I don't
remember incorrectly your grandfather
and Bernard pte chose stack leaves but
at that time there were what only two
wineries there um out of the six in Napa
there were there were close to 20
wineries in Napa Valley okay and Stags
sleep Wine sellers um was established
yeah and stag sleep Winery was
established shortly after us okay there
was not a lot of there were wasn't a lot
of wineries in that area at that time
time the vineyard that or the property
that we uh that we took on and then
eventually planted Vines and turned it
into a Vineyard was a combination of a
cattle farm prun Orchards and walnuts uh
and that was quite common in Napa Valley
in the 70s there was there was a lot of
tree nut uh farming activity there were
um prunes apple orchards pear Orchards
um not as much cattle and and sheep I
think that was still um predom l in in
Soma where there was just more more area
for for for grazing lar larger uh tracks
and Parcels but yeah by by the turn of
the of the decade into the 80s following
the the Judgment of parison what really
launched Napa Valley onto the scene of
an a area in the world where you can
make world class wines that a very
quickly started shifting all over to to
Grace what is the significant of or or
the uniqueness of Stags Le uh or
differences versus
other sub so as as I um talked about
briefly in the the topography so um the
Stags Leaf appalation is one of the
smaller appalachi in Napa Valley so uh
it's just over 1,200 Acres of vines so
it's quite a small area it sits on the I
would say the southern cortile of the
valley so it's quite a bit further south
so it is much closer to the mouth of or
the the base of some Bay mhm uh so you
get a lot of uh Coastal Marine influence
it's colder Co it's cooler so on the
East slope of the valley which is where
the STA B sits into the foothills of
that is volcanic so you have a lot of
volcanic rock and Ash influence in the
soils and there is this durapan which
flows through which over hundreds and
thousands of years slides down in so you
get a very complex soil structure within
within the uh Stags Le area so com
comination of obviously volcanic rock
and Ash you get some uh clay Lo so that
adds its complexity and then as you
mention the the the climate the
temperature so we get certainly cooler
evenings so when the Sun goes down the
temperature drops dramatically uh and
quite quickly and then when the fog
rolls in in the late uh summer and into
the fall because you have this pocket
that's created the fog rolls in and it
gets stuck and so it takes longer for it
to burn off in the morning basically you
get longer period where the grape can
recharge um as it's going through its um
its maturation Point uh towards Harvest
I so you get slightly more I think
balanced fruit where you're holding on
to the acidity within the fruit which is
great and important both for flavor but
also for ageability but you also then
get great Tannon development you get
that soft tannin structure but still are
able to to produce fruit that has great
flavor and intensity so it's it's a sort
of a a beautiful sort of Harmony between
the the different elements that you're
trying to capture and I think that's one
of the reasons why Bernard was so
excited about this place he felt
California's warmer than I ever he ever
experienced in Bordeaux but in this area
at least you get these cool nights well
yeah I mean Stags Le is the iconic one
of the first few iconic um AV areas so
so I I uh
I think it's familiar to the wine lovers
here in Taiwan uh this district and do
you know how many um wineries are there
now in style uh I should know this off
the top of my head I want to say there's
around 16 oh so very few still very few
and in in Napa Valley today there's
there's around 650 wow so it went all
the way from 21 when your grandfather
started and now 650 but stack Le still
remain quite exclusive so right now it's
about only 16 wi when why did you decide
to come back I mean I just told our fans
at the very beginning that officially
you're the first family members to be
Hands-On on a day-to-day management of
Winery right which is great we're all
very excited about it and you do have a
very big responsibility on you and I'm
sure a lot of markets a lot of people
that love clel expecting and and and and
excited to to wait for what to come in
the future but what what brought you
back so I think there uh a couple things
one I have since the beginning of of my
professional career have felt the
importance of privately owned you the
owner operator mentality I think it
brings a certain mindset and culture to
your organization where as an owner you
really can show the dedication and the
passion and the caring so I think that
is something that I before I took on
this job I used to work for a gentleman
who had started and built own company
and I felt the what a positive influence
and impact that gave me as an employee
someone who I was working for who was
there side by side every day helping
Drive the business forward and then I
think the second thing that so that was
for me from a personal standpoint and I
think my siblings and cousins we we all
agreed the same thing that if we're
going to do this for for the Next
Generation forward we should have that
kind of approach cuz that's something
that I think CL of struggled with a
little bit as my grandfather got older
there wasn't always a a very clear
alignment between the management and and
the owner uh and I so I think if you
have an owner or a representation of the
owner who is very engaged you ensure
that you have good alignment I think the
next thing um as we looked at the not
just the business but the industry this
this this is an industry that works in
decades not in in quarters or years and
so you're making you're making you're
making decisions whether they're
Financial investment decisions or
choices is from you know product
philosophy um brand um that really are
20 30 year decisions M and so if we were
going to continue to own this business
we should have that and there's no
better person to to lead that than
someone from the family so um as a as a
group of shareholders we we agreed if
we're going to if we're going to carry
this Legacy on for another 50 years it
should be one of us who's doing it or
else it's better to which I think you've
seen in not just in Napa Valley but
other places in in the wine industry and
I think this happens across Industries
family-owned businesses every time you
go through a generational change there's
a challenge to say we're going to go for
another cycle and I think we're
fortunate that we were very aligned in
how we were thinking about that's very
good it's it's it's it's very good I
think I think uh you made the right
decisions and and we're excited to see
how clel you'll lead clel in the next
decades many many decades that's good
okay now we're going to do a little fun
exercise that we will be uh reliving
trying to the Paris 1976 blind tasting
by Steven Spirit but in a very Mei
version okay so let's go exciting great
okay so Olaf as I was just explaining uh
three wines first tier is to pick out
which one we believe is CLO out okay
second tier is the other two wines that
we didn't pick out uh where are they
from and what grap are it you can pick
like the first one you can just like to
taste it smell and then describe what
what do you see okay okay ni all right
[Music]
[Applause]
you're done that was quick no I need I'm
between two yeah me too I need a little
[Music]
time
okay go ahead you got the I think it's
number two me too
yeah I think it's number too can you
tell why you get good fresh fruit
aromatics you get both red and some blue
fruit notes uh on the on the
nose I think the the pallet as well
there's good acidity to it so there's
there's some some mouth watering to it
without it being overly acidic it does
have some good depth and complexity and
it's got a nice long finish and I think
more than anything the the aromatics and
the mouth feel is what makes me think
it's about whereas I think three is a
little bit more earthy more red in
character uh I would guess that this is
probably oldw world uh Bordeaux not
quite sure I think this one is probably
also a new world one um this has a
little bit more Oak um on
it almost too and then what what I mean
one is very obvious so I had one and I
just put side because I know that's not
uh clot valve but two and three was so
difficult to choose because what ticks
it off is is that green earth exactly
that green earthy Aroma after I scroll
it for like 5 minutes
then this kind of Aroma yeah came out
and even though it's
so two is still very old world to me but
however the fress of the wine kind of
kind of showed a little bit more so
that's that's why I also choose to okay
so I will announce the answer for the
first round of the fine tasting so the
clo to all Napa Val cabin 2021 will be
the second yes the second one yes all
right man sir so the next round will be
guess uh the rest of two wi are the
region and and apparently the blend the
variety are all BR over you can tell the
Wier if you want
no no that only H that only happens in
comic books and movies I think this is a
a
bordeau wine
yeah uh I think it is predominantly
Cabernet silone yeah um I feel that in
the structure it's quite a linear one uh
there's not a lot of roundness and this
wine is perplexing me a little bit but I
I think this is a new this is this is a
California wine as well probably it's my
guess
or I'm having a harder time with this
one yeah me too I agree with Olaf that I
believe three is a bord
y uh I can't really distinguish if it's
left or right Bank but with the Tannon
structures it it's probably more on the
I would guess it's probably more on the
left than the right I mean I could be
wrong
but but um with with
one I think I have a
little probably I have a little uh lead
than you because this seems more even
though it's very
unilan but Chan yeah because recently
izus
uh which we carry and Edo they've been
trying to make wines that are very very
UN chillian in a way higher in acidity
so I would guess this is from Chile but
not a typical Chilean wine but more like
a erasus type where it's less robust and
less sweet and fruity it's it's it's
high in acidity right yeah but it's it's
an elegant line it's very elegant and
that's what I I think they're trying to
do to be very honest I I I don't know
but I do have a heads if if if if I'm
correct that is because it's we drink it
all the you know not all the time but we
taste it before yeah let's here it's
here W so both of you are really
professional and you are you are right
on the track so apparently the second
one will be the is called W so right
yeah you're right and the first one like
a well will be a little bit cheap
because this is the brand we carry so
it's a it's a chili Wine c
your yes well done I know I know I must
have had it for dinner last night no no
no I didn't because okay okay really I'm
right yeah and this is uh the elaser U
the flagship wine of Donald Max is $100
and is it is it um is it predominantly
Cabernet sovio yeah yes 100% no it's a
PL no but it's like 90 something yeah
and then the number three and the third
one was is from uh uh bordo okay so and
it's from actually it's from Red Bank
it's pom it's Pomo it's Pomo yeah it's
pom it's pretty powerful for Pomo but
the the the percent the blending
percentage is uh they use like a less
Mero but still dominant Mero but they
have a it is dominant Mero yeah usually
in per ho we have like like 70 or 80%
Malone but u in this shuttle they have
like a like a L cabin the cabin
FR wow so what house uh yeah it's a shut
PL oh plants plants from the moik family
torous it's it's good huh yeah yeah it's
good but but I have to say CL you see CL
stands among the best in how you dis
other the wine again I look for um the
fruit flavor intensity on the nose the
structure on the mouth so whether it's
the tannins again the acid and then are
there secondary and sort of tertiary
notes that can kind of lead lead the
pallet into One Direction uh from a
geographic standpoint or another so the
first one the max Maxi Mi yeah perplex
me a little bit I think partly I I just
I haven't had I haven't had a lot of
Chila wi but this is untypical no it's
very nice no it's untypical Chile and
white it's very elegant whereas most
Chilean wine this price point are very
you know full body full body and
powerful powerful so I think a good
challenge on these three wi good
challenge well anyway it's great choose
your favorite wine mine is definitely
number
two than thank you thanks for having me
thank you cheers
[Music]
everyone
okay for
[Music]
thank you all this is a great experience
than you sir thank you for
coming cheers okay well cheers again
cheers thank you
[Music]